Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have the beginning of a very long series on giving
我是Catherine，今天我们开始一个关于做演示的系列长课程。
a presentation.
演示。
So this series is at the intermediate level, right Marco?
这个系列是中级水平，对吧，Marco？
That's right.
没错。
It's part of our business series.
这是我们商务系列的一部分。
We previously took a look at how to go upon an interview.
我们之前学习了如何进行面试。
Now we're going to talk about presentation.
现在我们要讨论演示。
So everything about a presentation, how to give a presentation, language you can use
所以关于演示的一切，如何做演示，你在演示中能用的语言，
in a presentation and a lot of other things like this.
以及很多其他类似的内容。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to talk about the very beginning of a presentation.
我们要讨论演示的开头部分。
Let's take a listen to this dialogue and we'll be back in a moment.
让我们听一下这段对话，稍后回来。
Hi everyone.
大家好。
Can everyone hear me?
大家都能听到我吗？
Can you guys at the back hear everything?
后面的人能听清吗？
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon.
我想大家都知道我们今天下午为什么在这里。
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks an important moment for Alpha Computers.
正如你们大多数人知道的，2010年对Alpha Computers来说是一个重要时刻。
We have bounced back from the recession and now we are set to launch our new line of laptop
我们已经从经济衰退中反弹，现在准备推出我们的新系列笔记本电脑
and desktop computers.
和台式电脑。
I'm really pleased to welcome Michael Ford, the global marketing manager for Alpha Computers,
我很高兴欢迎Michael Ford，Alpha Computers的全球营销经理，
who has flown in from California to give all of you an overview of the marketing campaign
他从加州飞过来，给大家概述营销活动，
and to answer any questions you may have.
并回答你们可能有的任何问题。
So please, give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
所以，请热烈欢迎Ford先生。
Thank you, Jonathan.
谢谢你，Jonathan。
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
今天能在这里真的很荣幸。
It has been three years since I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that operations here
我上次访问北京已经是三年前了，很明显这里的运营
are obviously going from strength to strength.
正在蒸蒸日上。
The Alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds in China and that is certainly
Alpha品牌在中国持续飞速增长，这当然
down to the hard work of all of you here.
归功于在座各位的努力。
So congratulations to all of you.
所以恭喜大家。
I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation this afternoon and giving
我想先概述一下今天下午演示的要点，并给大家
you an idea of the topics that will be discussed.
一个将要讨论的主题的概念。
The presentation today is divided into five main parts.
今天的演示分为五个主要部分。
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X420 line, how the
首先，我想简要介绍一下新X420系列的背景，这个
whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our existing brand line.
整个概念是如何产生的，以及新产品如何融入我们现有的品牌线。
Secondly, I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X420.
其次，我想展示X420的预计销售数据。
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals in this sector.
然后我们将讨论我们在这一领域的主要竞争对手。
Then I'd like to go on to outline the campaign concept for the X420.
接着我想概述X420的活动概念。
Finally, I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions or points you may have for
最后，我很乐意开放讨论，回答大家可能有的任何问题或
me.
观点。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So as you can see, it's the very beginning of a presentation.
所以正如你们看到的，这是演示的开头部分。
We're kind of starting to give people an idea what we're going to talk about.
我们开始让大家了解我们将要讨论的内容。
So let's take a look at some of the language Mr. Ford used on Language Takeaway.
让我们看看Ford先生在“语言要点”中使用的一些语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So the reason Mr. Ford is giving a presentation is because he wants to talk about the company's
所以Ford先生做演示的原因是他想谈论公司的新
new line of computers, right?
电脑系列，对吧？
And so he says that they're going to launch a new line of desktop and laptop computers.
他说他们要推出一个新的台式机和笔记本电脑系列。
That's right.
没错。
So they want to launch a new line of laptops.
所以他们想推出一个新的笔记本电脑系列。
So this verb to launch means to bring out to the market.
所以动词“launch”意思是推向市场。
That's right.
没错。
So instead of the word to start, which you could use in many different ways, like to
所以不是用“start”这个词，这个词可以用在很多不同场合，比如
start eating or to start swimming.
开始吃饭或开始游泳。
In this case, to launch means you're going to introduce a new product to the market.
在这种情况下，“launch”意味着你要向市场推出一个新产品。
Like you said, Marco.
就像你说的，Marco。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to start selling to the market a new product.
所以我们要开始向市场销售一个新产品。
We're going to launch a new line of laptop and desktop computers.
我们要推出一个新的笔记本电脑和台式电脑系列。
For example, this spring, Steve Jobs launched the iPad, which is a new product.
例如，今年春天，Steve Jobs推出了iPad，这是一个新产品。
That's right.
没错。
So he launched the iPad and the iPhone 4.
所以他推出了iPad和iPhone 4。
They're always launching new things at Apple.
苹果公司总是在推出新东西。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好的。
So since they're launching this new line of laptop and desktop computers, Mr. Ford first
既然他们要推出这个新的笔记本电脑和台式电脑系列，Ford先生首先
wanted to give a brief overview of the marketing campaign.
想简要概述一下营销活动。
Okay.
好的。
So first of all, we're going to talk about how this product is being marketed.
所以首先，我们要讨论这个产品是如何营销的。
So you want to give a general picture or a very simple picture of what's going to happen.
所以你想给出一个总体画面或一个非常简单的画面，说明将要发生什么。
So at the beginning, this will happen.
所以一开始，会发生这个。
Then this will happen at the end.
然后最后会发生这个。
This will happen.
会发生这个。
And that's what we call an overview.
这就是我们所说的概述。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a brief or general idea of what we're talking about.
所以这是对我们讨论内容的一个简要或总体的概念。
An overview, nothing too specific.
一个概述，不要太具体。
We just want to give you a general idea.
我们只是想给你一个总体概念。
That's right.
没错。
After that, Mr. Ford starts talking and he's talking about the presentation, which has
之后，福特先生开始讲话，他谈到了演示文稿，这份文稿包含
many parts, and he wants to talk about what each part will contain.
很多部分，他想讨论每个部分的内容。
So he says, I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X420 line.
所以他说，我想简要谈谈新款X420系列的背景。
So this verb, to touch on.
所以这个动词，to touch on。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
So when he says he wants to touch on the background of this new computer, he's basically saying,
所以当他说他想谈谈这款新电脑的背景时，他基本上是在说，
I want to talk about.
我想讨论一下。
All right.
好的。
So this is potentially very confusing because we know the word to touch means to put your
这可能会让人很困惑，因为我们知道单词touch的意思是把手
hand on something.
放在某物上。
But to touch on, this is a phrasal verb, this means to talk about or to address.
但to touch on是一个短语动词，意思是谈论或提及。
That's right.
没错。
So for example, a teacher at a university will touch on many topics during his lecture.
例如，大学老师会在讲座中涉及许多话题。
That's right.
没错。
Or I'd like to touch on where we're going to dinner tonight because I'm very hungry.
或者我想谈谈今晚我们去哪里吃晚饭，因为我很饿。
Okay.
好的。
So basically it's a nice way of saying, I want to talk about this topic.
所以基本上这是一种礼貌的说法，表示我想讨论这个话题。
And then apart from touching on the background of the new computer, he said he also wants
除了谈论新电脑的背景，他还说他想
to talk about projected sales for this new computer.
讨论这款新电脑的预计销量。
Okay.
好的。
So projected sales, this phrase includes two words.
所以预计销量这个短语包含两个词。
Sales means how much of something you sell, obviously, but projected means what you expect
销量显然是指你卖出了多少东西，但预计是指你预期
to sell.
要卖出的数量。
So the projected sales have not happened yet.
所以预计销量还没有发生。
They will happen in the future.
它们会在未来发生。
And so they're basically my guess about sales.
所以它们基本上是我对销量的猜测。
That's right.
没错。
So basically we are giving an estimate of what we think we will sell.
所以基本上我们是在给出一个估计，关于我们认为会卖出多少。
Those are projected sales.
那些就是预计销量。
We think we will sell a thousand computers.
我们认为我们会卖出一千台电脑。
Those are our projected sales.
那些是我们的预计销量。
Right.
对。
And after that, we have one more key word.
之后，我们还有一个关键词。
This word comes at the very end of the speech.
这个词出现在演讲的最后。
Mr. Ford says, we will then go on to discuss our key rivals.
福特先生说，然后我们会继续讨论我们的主要竞争对手。
Now who is a rival, Marco?
那么，马可，什么是竞争对手？
Okay.
好的。
So a rival is basically your competitor or maybe kind of your enemy.
所以竞争对手基本上就是你的竞争者，或者有点像你的敌人。
All right.
好的。
So in computers, who is Apple's rival?
那么在电脑领域，谁是苹果的竞争对手？
Maybe HP or IBM or Dell.
可能是惠普、IBM或戴尔。
Very good.
很好。
So a rival is someone you compete with.
所以竞争对手就是和你竞争的人。
That's right.
没错。
So he's going to talk about his key rivals.
所以他打算讨论他的主要竞争对手。
So basically the word key is your most important rivals.
所以基本上key这个词指的是最重要的竞争对手。
All right.
好的。
So for example, who is one of Batman's key rivals?
例如，谁是蝙蝠侠的主要竞争对手之一？
Because we have rivals not just in business, but also in life.
因为我们不仅在商业中有竞争对手，生活中也有。
That's right.
没错。
So I think maybe Batman's key rival might be the Joker.
所以我想蝙蝠侠的主要竞争对手可能是小丑。
Or the Penguin.
或者企鹅人。
All right.
好的。
So let's take another listen to today's dialogue and we'll be back in a moment with some very
那么让我们再听一遍今天的对话，我们稍后会回来介绍一些非常
important phrases.
重要的短语。
Hi, everyone.
大家好。
Can everyone hear me?
大家都能听到我吗？
Can you guys at the back hear everything?
后面的人能听到一切吗？
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon.
我想大家都知道我们今天下午为什么在这里。
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks an important moment for Alpha Computers.
正如你们大多数人所知，2010年对Alpha电脑公司来说是一个重要的时刻。
We have bounced back from the recession and now we are set to launch our new line of laptop
我们已经从经济衰退中恢复过来，现在准备推出我们的新系列笔记本电脑
and desktop computers.
和台式电脑。
I'm really pleased to welcome Michael Ford, the global marketing manager for Alpha Computers,
我非常高兴地欢迎迈克尔·福特，Alpha电脑公司的全球营销经理，
who has flown in from California to give all of you an overview of the marketing campaign
他从加利福尼亚飞过来，向大家概述营销活动
and to answer any questions you may have.
并回答你们可能有的任何问题。
So please, give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
所以，请大家热烈欢迎福特先生。
Thank you, Jonathan.
谢谢你，乔纳森。
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
今天能来到这里真的很荣幸。
It has been three years since I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that operations here
自从我上次访问北京已经三年了，我清楚地看到这里的业务
are obviously going from strength to strength.
显然在蒸蒸日上。
The Alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds in China and that is certainly
Alpha品牌在中国继续飞速发展，这当然
down to the hard work of all of you here.
归功于在座各位的努力。
So congratulations to all of you.
所以祝贺大家。
I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation this afternoon and giving
我想先概述一下今天下午演示文稿的要点，并让
you an idea of the topics that will be discussed.
你们了解将要讨论的话题。
The presentation today is divided into five main parts.
今天的演示文稿分为五个主要部分。
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X420 line, how the
首先，我想简要谈谈新款X420系列的背景，以及如何
whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our existing brand line.
整个概念是如何产生的，以及新产品如何融入我们现有的品牌线。
Secondly, I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X420.
其次，我想展示X420的预计销售数据。
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals in this sector.
然后我们将继续讨论我们在这一领域的主要竞争对手。
Then I'd like to go on to outline the campaign concept for the X420.
接着我想继续概述X420的宣传活动方案。
Finally, I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions or points you may have for
最后，我很乐意开放讨论，回答你们可能提出的任何问题或观点。
me.
我。
All right, so we've prepared three phrases for you.
好的，我们为你准备了三个短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们在Fluency Builder上看看这些短语。
Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder。
So this first phrase is really important because it's about the part of the speech that happens
所以第一个短语非常重要，因为它涉及演讲开始前的那部分内容。
before the speech begins.
在演讲开始之前。
You know, usually you have a person who's going to talk about something, but you also
你知道，通常有一个人要谈论某事，但还有另一个人介绍那个人。
have someone who introduces that person.
有一个人介绍那个人。
You know, this is John.
你知道，这是约翰。
He's going to talk about computers.
他要谈论电脑。
He's very smart.
他非常聪明。
Listen to everything he says.
听他说的一切。
So we usually hear the phrase, let's give a warm welcome to.
所以我们通常听到这个短语：让我们热烈欢迎。
Yes, this is a very nice way of presenting someone.
是的，这是介绍某人时非常友好的方式。
So obviously this person is talking to a group of people and he's introducing Mr. Ford.
所以显然这个人正在对一群人说话，他在介绍福特先生。
So he says, let's give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
所以他说，让我们热烈欢迎福特先生。
So that's saying let's clap.
这就是说让我们鼓掌。
Let's say hello to him.
让我们向他问好。
That's right.
没错。
So like you said, this is an invitation to clap.
就像你说的，这是邀请鼓掌。
You have to clap when you hear this.
当你听到这个时，你必须鼓掌。
Warm welcome means let's be nice to him.
热烈欢迎意味着让我们对他友好。
Let's all smile and encourage him.
让我们都微笑并鼓励他。
You know, you think about it.
你知道，想想看。
Someone who's going to give a speech is probably nervous.
一个要发表演讲的人可能很紧张。
And so this helps them feel comfortable.
所以这能帮助他们感到舒适。
That's right.
没错。
So it's a very nice way if you're maybe presenting someone who's going to talk, you can say,
所以如果你要介绍一个将要发言的人，这是一种很好的方式，你可以说，
let's give a warm welcome to whoever you're presenting.
让我们热烈欢迎你介绍的那个人。
Okay.
好的。
Now when Mr. Ford was talking, he mentioned this very interesting phrase about operations.
现在当福特先生说话时，他提到了一个关于运营的非常有趣的短语。
He said, it's clear to me that operations here are obviously going from strength to
他说，我很清楚这里的运营显然在蒸蒸日上。
strength.
蒸蒸日上。
Okay.
好的。
So that means things are going well.
所以这意味着事情进展顺利。
You do one thing, you do it well.
你做一件事，做得很好。
You move on to another thing, you do that well as well.
你继续做另一件事，也做得很好。
Okay.
好的。
So that's what it means from strength to strength.
所以这就是“蒸蒸日上”的意思。
So we're saying that things are going from good to better.
所以我们说事情从好变得更好。
That's right.
没错。
And getting better.
并且越来越好。
Okay.
好的。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们的最后一个短语呢？
Our last phrase is kind of similar to the last one.
我们的最后一个短语和上一个有点类似。
The alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds.
Alpha品牌继续突飞猛进地增长。
All right.
好的。
So you can have a company that grows.
所以你可以有一个增长的公司。
It grows a little.
它增长一点点。
You can have a company that grows quite a bit.
你可以有一个增长相当多的公司。
Then you have a company that grows in leaps and bounds.
然后你有一个突飞猛进增长的公司。
That means a lot.
这意味着增长很多。
Okay.
好的。
So to leap is to jump, right?
所以“leap”是跳跃的意思，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
And so this is what we're saying.
这就是我们想说的。
We're just jumping higher and higher.
我们只是跳得越来越高。
We're getting bigger and bigger or better and better.
我们变得越来越大或越来越好。
That's right.
没错。
So this is an exaggeration.
所以这是一种夸张的说法。
It's like saying that it's not going quickly.
就像说它不是在快速前进。
It's going the speed of light.
而是以光速前进。
You know, it's just so fast.
你知道，就是这么快。
All of a sudden, just really growing.
突然之间，真的在增长。
Okay.
好的。
A lot of interesting phrases there.
那里有很多有趣的短语。
A lot of key vocab.
很多关键词汇。
I think we can listen to this dialogue again.
我想我们可以再听一遍这段对话。
And we'll be back in a bit.
我们一会儿回来。
Hi, everyone.
大家好。
Can everyone hear me?
大家都能听到我吗？
Can you guys at the back hear everything?
后面的人都能听到吗？
I think all of you know why we are here this afternoon.
我想你们都知道今天下午我们为什么在这里。
As most of you are aware, 2010 marks an important moment for alpha computers.
正如你们大多数人所知，2010年对Alpha电脑来说是一个重要时刻。
We have bounced back from the recession and now we are set to launch our new line of laptop
我们已经从经济衰退中反弹，现在准备推出我们的新笔记本电脑系列。
and desktop computers.
还有台式电脑。
I'm really pleased to welcome Michael Ford, the global marketing manager for alpha computers,
我非常高兴地欢迎迈克尔·福特，他是阿尔法电脑的全球营销经理。
who has flown in from California to give all of you an overview of the marketing campaign
他从加利福尼亚飞过来，为大家概述这次营销活动。
and to answer any questions you may have.
并回答你们可能提出的任何问题。
So please, give a warm welcome to Mr. Ford.
所以，请大家热烈欢迎福特先生。
Thank you, Jonathan.
谢谢你，乔纳森。
It really is a pleasure to be here today.
今天能来到这里真的很荣幸。
It has been three years since I visited Beijing and it's clear to me that operations here
自从我上次访问北京已经三年了，我清楚地看到这里的业务。
are obviously going from strength to strength.
显然在蒸蒸日上。
The alpha brand continues to grow in leaps and bounds in China and that is certainly
阿尔法品牌在中国持续飞速发展，这当然。
down to the hard work of all of you here.
归功于在座各位的辛勤工作。
So congratulations to all of you.
所以，祝贺大家。
I'd like to start by outlining the key points of my presentation this afternoon and giving
我想先概述一下今天下午演讲的要点，并让大家。
you an idea of the topics that will be discussed.
了解将要讨论的主题。
The presentation today is divided into five main parts.
今天的演讲分为五个主要部分。
First of all, I'd like to briefly touch on the background of the new X420 line, how the
首先，我想简要介绍一下新X420系列的背景，这个。
whole concept has come about and how the new product fits into our existing brand line.
整个概念是如何产生的，以及新产品如何融入我们现有的品牌线。
Secondly, I'd like to present data on projected sales for the X420.
其次，我想展示X420的预计销售数据。
We will then go on to discuss our key rivals in this sector.
然后我们将讨论我们在这一领域的主要竞争对手。
Then I'd like to go on to outline the campaign concept for the X420.
接着，我想概述X420的宣传活动概念。
Finally, I'm happy to open up the discussion for any questions or points you may have for
最后，我很乐意开放讨论，回答你们可能提出的任何问题或观点。
me.
Alright, so as we mentioned, this is the first part of a ten-part series all about public
好的，正如我们提到的，这是关于公共演讲和做演示的十集系列的第一部分。
speaking, giving a presentation.
We're going to talk about many aspects of a presentation like charts and graphs and
我们将讨论演示的许多方面，比如图表和图形。
using PowerPoint, all these really modern ways of giving a presentation.
以及使用PowerPoint，所有这些非常现代的演示方式。
That's right and we're going to try and talk to you about some of the places in presentations
没错，我们还会尝试和你们谈谈演示中那些。
that English learners tend to struggle with.
英语学习者往往感到困难的地方。
You know, it's sometimes very hard to know what to say, especially like in today's lesson,
你知道，有时候很难知道该说什么，尤其是在今天的课程中。
how do you introduce someone in a presentation?
如何在演示中介绍某人？
It's not very common to learn how to say that.
学会怎么说这个并不常见。
So we hope that through these podcasts, you'll be able to learn some really important phrases
所以我们希望通过这些播客，你们能学到一些非常重要的短语。
and become more comfortable while you're giving presentations in English.
并在用英语做演示时变得更自在。
That's right.
没错。
And of course, if you have any questions about these lessons or any of our lessons, you can
当然，如果你们对这些课程或我们的任何课程有疑问，可以。
always find us at EnglishPod.com or you can send us also your suggestions about any lesson
随时在EnglishPod.com找到我们，或者你也可以发送关于任何课程主题的建议。
topics you may have.
That's right.
没错。
So we hope to hear from you.
所以我们希望能收到你们的消息。
Please let us know what you're thinking and until next time everyone.
请告诉我们你的想法，下次再见，各位。
Bye.
再见。
Thank you.
谢谢。